<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Seattle | rohan singh]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rohanradio.com/blog/categories/seattle/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rohanradio.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-05T01:29:30+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rohanradio.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rohan Singh]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Far From Home?]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rohanradio.com/blog/2012/09/30/how-far-from-home/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-30T22:12:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rohanradio.com/blog/2012/09/30/how-far-from-home</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just like every other Bob Dylan fan in the world, I have been endeavoring to
determine exactly how many roads a man must walk down. To this end, I've been
using passive location tracking for a few years now and have generated a fairly
significant amount of data on my movements and travel. Mostly I've used
<a href="http://latitude.google.com/">Google Latitude</a>, and enabled its optional history
feature.</p>

<p>Many people shudder at the privacy implications of this. Personally, I assume
my cell phone providers have very similar data on hand already, if not with
quite as much accuracy and precision.</p>

<p>I've now started looking through the data to see how my movements have changed
over time. One really stark difference between living in Seattle and living in
Stockholm is my average furthest distance — on any given day how many miles away
from home do I make it?</p>

<p>Check it out. This a map of my movements in Seattle on Thursday, September 29, 2011:</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/roads/seattle-20110929.png"></p>

<p>That was a fairly normal Thursday on which I went downtown for work, went back
home, and then went out for drinks on Capitol Hill. One cool thing about having
this data is that it helps spark your memory — I now remember that exact
evening, who I was with, and some of the conversations that we were having.
Location is an excellent trigger for that sort of thing.</p>

<p>Anyway, you can see that the furthest I made it from home is <strong>4.3 miles</strong>. Most
of my days in Seattle seem to have a furthest distance figure of 4 to 6 miles.</p>

<p>Now, here's a map of my movements in Stockholm on this Wednesday, September 26, 2012:</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/roads/stockholm-20120926.png"></p>

<p>Again, a fairly normal Wednesday. I walked to the office, went to a show after
work, and then walked home. The difference, though, is that the furthest I made
it from home is only <strong>0.997 miles</strong>.</p>

<p>One mile instead of five miles. That's a pretty significant difference. What
makes it especially interesting for me is that I lived pretty centrally in Seattle
and had a very enviable commute (15 minutes on the bus followed by 5 minutes
on a bike).</p>

<p>The same holds in Stockholm. I live fairly centrally and have a similarly short
commute. But the difference is that in Stockholm a short commute is a 15-minute walk,
rather than a 15-minute bus ride. This is the kind of thing you can enable when
you build for density, and it's the kind of thing I hope to see become more
possible in Seattle as well.</p>

<p>Some caveats here:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Neither of these days were climbing days for me, so I didn't make it to the
climbing gym. If I look at climbing days, my distance from home in Seattle is
about 6 miles. In Stockholm it's either 2 or 4 miles depending on which gym.
That's definitely a less pronounced difference, but I think the theme still
holds.</p></li>
<li><p>Some neighborhoods in Seattle are fairly dense. On my stereotypical lazy Sundays
spent in and around <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wallingford,_Seattle">Wallingford</a>,
I often didn't make it even 2 miles from home. I could walk to restaurants,
the coffee shop, the beer shop and the pub without going even half a mile.
But unlike in Stockholm, that half a mile isn't dense enough to have many
offices where a software engineer might be able to find employment. Rather,
I had to go downtown for work.</p></li>
<li><p>While I have a bunch of data points about myself and my movements, this whole
thing is — at its heart — quite anecdotal. I'm sure there are people
in Seattle who don't usually have to go more than a mile from home. And I know
there are people in Stockholm who live further out and have to commute a few
miles.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>Anyway, just some data that I thought was interesting.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
