<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Music | rohan singh]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rohanradio.com/blog/categories/music/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rohanradio.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-08T00:02:07+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rohanradio.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rohan Singh]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Discovered — Winter 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rohanradio.com/blog/2013/02/06/discovered-winter-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-06T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rohanradio.com/blog/2013/02/06/discovered-winter-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><small><em>Statements and opinions that follow are entirely my own</em></small></p>

<p>One thing I'm excited about lately are the brand new music discovery features we're working on at
Spotify. If you haven't heard, here's a sneak peek:</p>

<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/mcndH5zvm6U?feature=player_detailpage" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>Discovering new music is brilliant, even if it's just new to <em>you</em> and everyone else heard it years
ago. As part of a generation that largely didn't experience it, I finally have some understanding
of what people loved about the "sifting through albums at the record store" experience of yesteryear.
Personalized music discovery is awesome.</p>

<p>In that vein, I thought I'd share some of the new music that I've discovered over the past month or
so. These artists and tracks aren't specifically <em>new</em>, but they were all new to me. If you just want
the TL;DR, <a href="http://open.spotify.com/user/rohanrsingh/playlist/31nT82bgnsMpdSRS5PCILh">here is the <em>Discovered: Winter 2013</em> playlist</a>
that I put together. It's a shorter list that I've found works excellently for seeding a radio station.</p>

<p>Now let me talk a bit about these artists, from a Portland outfit that did a literal <em>bicycle tour</em>
of the Pacific Coast, to an indie band who used Kickstarter to make their next album possible, to a
socially conscious rapper from Nova Scotia.</p>

<h2>Bronze Radio Return (Hartford, CT)</h2>

<iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify:album:0hO7tdTpSVN1ADtLbvJiQ5&theme=white&view=coverart"
    width="250" height="330" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"
    style="float:left;margin-right:30px;"></iframe>


<p>This indie rock band hails from Connecticut, and performed for Barack Obama in 2010. This album,
<em>Shake! Shake! Shake!</em>, is actually from 2011, but Bronze Radio Return is <a href="http://bronzeradioreturn.com/">still alive and kicking</a>.</p>

<p>There's a good chance you heard the eponymous  <a href="http://open.spotify.com/track/4dI4oscajpdtjpg2dP1x28">"Shake, Shake, Shake"</a>
when it was featured in a Nissan Leaf commercial. I first heard it as I was
running to the subway through a snowstorm in Stockholm, and it fit perfectly.</p>

<p>It's one of those songs that has a slower start but then suddenly turns into
an entirely different beast. When I arrived at the bar where I met my friends,
the first thing I did was to take off my headphones and foist them upon my
unsuspecting companions, making them listen to "Shake, Shake, Shake" before
I even got around to ordering a beer.</p>

<p>Another of my favorite tracks is <a href="http://open.spotify.com/track/1d6rwEAWQ4zx2ArgIBTVmc">"Down There"</a>, which brings
back all my memories of hanging out by the river during the summer after high school. While I realize
that Bronze Radio Return is probably thinking of a river in New England while I'm thinking of
a very specific river in the Pacific Northwest, the whole experience is still very Americana.</p>

<p>Overall, the whole album served as an excellent for snowboarding in the northwest over the holidays,
including for the drives to and from the slopes. And if you're heading to <a href="http://sxsw.com">SXSW</a>
this year, you're in luck. Bronze Radio Return will be playing on March 11.</p>

<h2>Great Lake Swimmers (Toronto, Ontario, Canada)</h2>

<iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify:album:5RArdv6T3ck7BmZHI7inmz&theme=white&view=coverart"
    width="250" height="330" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"
    style="float:right;margin-left:30px;"></iframe>


<p>If there was a band that I could say characterizes what I think of when I think of Canadian indie
folk, this would be it.</p>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Lake_Swimmers">Great Lake Swimmers</a>
is a folk rock group from Toronto, and you can almost <em>hear</em> the geography of Ontario in their music.
At the core, communicating about their environment is what these guys are about. Tony Dekker, the
lead vocalist, actually contributed a <a href="http://blog.wwf.ca/blog/2013/01/23/tony-dekker-on-the-physical-spiritual-and-philosophical-connection-between-music-and-nature/">short piece on this to the WWF</a>.</p>

<p>Overall, I'd say that my favorite Great Lake Swimmers album is <em><a href="http://open.spotify.com/album/5RArdv6T3ck7BmZHI7inmz">Ongiara</a></em>,
their 2008 release. Definitely worth a listen.</p>

<p>As for the latest album, <em>New Wild Everywhere</em>, I haven't gotten around to it yet but there's actually
<a href="http://open.spotify.com/album/0tT8zJriwVQXccHxQLiqGB">a version with track-by-track commentary from the band</a>
available.</p>

<h2>Blind Pilot (Portland, OR)</h2>

<iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify:album:6eLMGMZE8Kv9lCGCk551Bu&theme=white&view=coverart"
    width="250" height="330" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"
    style="float:left;margin-right:30px;"></iframe>


<p>From the other side of the continent, we have <a href="http://blindpilot.com">Blind Pilot</a>. These folks
started small, and I got a kick reading about their 2008 bicycle tour.</p>

<p>Apparently they built some trailers, tossed their instruments in, and proceeded to bicycle to gigs
all the way from Bellingham to San Diego (incidentally, two of my favorite towns).</p>

<p>That's definitely one way to earn some West Coast cred. I've driven the
Pacific Coast Highway a couple times, and it is nearly a spiritual experience. I regret not joining
friends who have bicycled it.</p>

<p>As it is, the whole <em><a href="http://open.spotify.com/album/6eLMGMZE8Kv9lCGCk551Bu">3 Rounds and a Sound</a></em> album from
2008 makes for some very chill listening. I took an immediate liking to the folksy lead-in
of <a href="http://open.spotify.com/track/2LozqICm38mBX3yseiyOWa">"One Red Thread"</a>. For some reason it
really reminds me of <a href="http://open.spotify.com/track/164gAwPYaCpFRfpDabXQON">"Yankee Bayonet"</a> from
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Decemberists">The Decemberists</a>.</p>

<h2>Wild Child (Austin, TX)</h2>

<iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify:album:6PPFActErBg9LwXfMfOKYB&theme=white&view=coverart"
    width="250" height="330" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"
    style="float:right;margin-left:30px;"></iframe>


<p><a href="http://wildchildsounds.com">Wild Child</a> describe themselves as a "folk-pop" band from Austin. Their
debut album, <em><a href="http://open.spotify.com/album/6PPFActErBg9LwXfMfOKYB">Pillow Talk</a></em>, was released back in 2011.</p>

<p>Between Kelsey Wilson and Alex Beggins, <em>Pillow Talk</em> features the same back-and-forth vocals that
make <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DHEOF_rcND8">Edward Sharpe</a>
so compelling. And it makes you want to sing along in the same way that <a href="http://open.spotify.com/track/0uZ0orE84drZZzPKxCWSmR">"Little Talks"</a>
does.</p>

<p>Whisky seems to be a frequent subject matter of <em>Pillow Talk</em>. I'd say that my personal favorite tracks
from this album are <a href="http://open.spotify.com/track/5l7lNSHzTpVtd6Gee8XjUE">"Whiskey Dreams"</a> and
<a href="http://open.spotify.com/track/7rJeqhxvReMhpq5ylDO3Bf">"Cocaine Hurricane"</a>.</p>

<p>I did some searching and thought that Wild Child had dropped off the face of the planet after their
first album, but the truth is much better. They're recording their sophomore effort, <em>The Runaround</em>,
with funds they <a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/wildchild/wild-child-is-making-a-new-album-with-ben-kweller">raised on Kickstarter</a>.
So cool.</p>

<h2>Quiet Company, Boy &amp; Bear, Urban Cone &amp; more</h2>

<p>Here's what else made it into my <a href="http://open.spotify.com/user/rohanrsingh/playlist/31nT82bgnsMpdSRS5PCILh"><em>Discovered: Winter 2013</em> playlist</a>:</p>

<iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify:user:rohanrsingh:playlist:31nT82bgnsMpdSRS5PCILh&theme=white"
    width="300" height="380" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"
    style="float:right;margin-left:30px;margin-bottom:10px;"></iframe>


<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quiet_Company">Quiet Company</a> is another indie band from Austin.
Very reminiscient of Death Cab, but with a more upbeat touch.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boy_%26_Bear">Boy &amp; Bear</a> are a folk rock quintet from Sydney. I
particularly love the sound of <a href="http://open.spotify.com/track/4HopuG8wQBlvXQ6xwA79FG">"Fall At Your Feet"</a>,
their tribute to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Finn_Brothers">Tim &amp; Neil Finn</a>.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/urbancone">Urban Cone</a> is an indie pop band that's gotten a pretty big
following here among Stockholm natives. Take a look at their <a href="http://open.spotify.com/album/0TNzAX4rt4Efeth6eEfvxD">Urban Photograph</a>
release.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Classified_(rapper">Classified</a> is an indie hip-hop artist from Nova Scotia who rhymes about the day-to-day with tracks like
<a href="http://open.spotify.com/track/3J2ZYJkhxGBOl3L8K4XGVu">"Pay Day"</a>. Really reminds of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blue_Scholars">Blue Scholars</a>
from Seattle.</p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.asafavidanmusic.com/">Asaf Avidan</a>, hailing from Jerusalem, is an artist I probably
should have heard about by now. In my defense, his earlier releases never made it to the USA. The
<a href="http://open.spotify.com/album/7KvEzNiTPrAPIbBILMLwQx">album of One Day (Reckoning Song) remixes</a> is
great music to work and crank out some code to.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Well, here's to a year that I'm sure is going to be filled with excellent music.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
