<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Beer | rohan singh]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rohanradio.com/blog/categories/beer/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rohanradio.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-01T01:53:39+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rohanradio.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rohan Singh]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stone Sublimely Self-Righteous]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rohanradio.com/blog/2011/12/26/stone-sublimely-self-righteous/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-26T19:56:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rohanradio.com/blog/2011/12/26/stone-sublimely-self-righteous</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every winter for the past few years, I've spent at least a weekend in San Diego.
Not only is the tropical sun a great respite from gloomy Seattle, but San Diego
— against all odds and expectations — is a brilliant beer town, and home to the
iconic <a href="http://www.stonebrew.com">Stone Brewing Co</a>.</p>

<p>To get myself into the right mindset for my upcoming trip, tonight I am
enjoying Stone's <em>Sublimely Self-Righteous Ale</em>. As frequent drinkers of Stone
are surely aware, that brewery is full of <a href="http://www.stonebrew.com/arrogantbastard">downright bastards</a>.</p>

<p>Which is why I just had to share this brilliant excerpt from the label on the
back of this dastardly, <a href="http://www.stonebrew.com/sublimely/">self-rightous bottle</a>:</p>

<blockquote><p>Yes, we damn well know our stuff here at Stone, and it would be irresponsible
of us to not acknowledge how remarkable this heavenly creation of ours is. Thus
the name we are compelled to give it — Stone Sublimely Self-Rightous Ale –
serves as a reminder of just how good we are, in both liquid and verbal form.</p></blockquote>

<p>And also:</p>

<blockquote><p>When you're good, you're good. And when you do something great, the least you
can do is acknowledge it. Others benefit from knowing.</p></blockquote>

<p>For the record, this self-righteous ale lives up to its label and leaves a smile
on your face — or, at least, on mine.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
