<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Reading | rohan singh]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.rohanradio.com/blog/categories/reading/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.rohanradio.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-06-18T11:18:50-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.rohanradio.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rohan Singh]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I've Been Reading (Dec. 26, 2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.rohanradio.com/blog/2011/12/26/what-ive-been-reading-december-26/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-26T14:12:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.rohanradio.com/blog/2011/12/26/what-ive-been-reading-december-26</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What follows are the most insightful, interesting, or otherwise
noteworthy articles I've stumbled across over the past couple weeks.</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://www.readability.com/articles/hvn0le5e">Democracy is not a truth machine</a></strong>.
One of the best articles I've read all week. In it, a bearded philosopher
eloquently demonstrates why democratic processes can't be trusted to find
the truth about objective facts about reality. For example, while a democratic
process can be used to decide what we <em>should do</em> about climate change, the
underlying scientific reality is not up for debate.</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://www.salon.com/2011/12/03/the_evolution_of_monsters/singleton/">Why we invented monsters</a></strong>.
Paul Carr start with the idea that monsters grew into the human
consciousness in the image of predators, such as felines and
snakes. Eventually, as protohumans transformed from a prey species into
predators, our imaginations transformed as well.</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/magazine-16037798">The scandal of the Alabama poor cut off from water</a></strong>.
It really kills me that we need a foreign news source to report about the fact
that America's infrastructure is failing and the promises of citizenship
aren't panning out for some of those who have the greatest need.
Reading this article, others like it, and watching the documentary
<em><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Waiting_for_%22Superman%22">Waiting for "Superman"</a></em>
over the weekend has left me with a lot of questions in a place where there
are few good answers.</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2011/12/why-americas-death-penalty-just-got-us-sanctioned-by-europe/250324/">Why America's Death Penalty Just Got Us Sanctioned by Europe</a></strong>.
The European Union has decided that it will have no part in the barbarism
involved in the methodical killing of human beings by their peers. I
completely agree with Ford Vox's characterization of the situation:</p>

<blockquote><p>The death penalty is a blind spot in our democracy, our own peculiar
national <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anosognosia">anosognosia</a>.
It probably will take the rest of the world shouting
us down in order to recognize our impairment.</p></blockquote></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://www.remappingdebate.org/article/tale-two-systems">A tale of two systems</a></strong>.
The folks at <a href="http://www.remappingdebate.org/">Remapping Debate</a> contrast a
failing labor system in America with a robust, unionized system in Germany.</p></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://www.samharris.org/blog/item/hitch/">Hitch</a></strong>. Sam Harris, eloquent
as always, on Christopher Hitchens' death:</p>

<blockquote><p>Needless to say, he was effortlessly lucid and witty—and taking no prisoners.
There should be a name for the peculiar cocktail of emotion I then enjoyed:
one part astonishment, one part relief, two parts envy; stir. It would not be
the last time I drank it in his honor.</p></blockquote></li>
<li><p><strong><a href="http://rrs.co/tlMGyE">Freakonomics: What Went Wrong?</a></strong>. Andrew Gelman and
Kaiser Fung examine many of the conclusions in <em>Freakonomics</em> and
<em>Superfreakonomics</em> which have worked themselves into the cultural
consciousness and which are now taken for granted. Specifically, they show
that many of these conclusions are just plain wrong.</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
